JITHIN K

Senior Engineer

**** +91 9562149569



k.jithin12@gmail.com

Profile

I am a passionate software engineer with 4+ years experience in analysis, design, and development of iOS applications. Have extensive programming skills in Swift and solid understanding of mobile application development lifecycle. Now seeking new opportunities to further expand on these skills and learn new technologies.

Education

B.Tech, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2011 - 2015

Government College of Engineering Kannur

Relevant Skills

- Xcode, Swift, Auto Layout
- Core Data, Core Bluetooth
- Health Kit
- APNS, In-app purchase
- REST APIs, Git
- Firebase, Google Analytics
- JIRA, Agile Development
- CI/CD, CocoaPods
- Angular

Professional Experience

Dec 2018 - Present **OBurst**

Senior Engineer

July 2015 - Dec 2018 **Cabot Technology Solutions**

Software Engineer

Projects

Banani- A real estate application which allows users to add their properties and apartments and list them for rental.

Four Four Two- An app providing users with the latest football news, live scores, and commentary from various leagues and competitions.

Wealth Advisors iPad App- An application developed for Wealth Advisors (India) Pvt Ltd, which operates as an independent, full-service, client-centric investment solutions firm. The app is used by their advisors/managers who deal with the clients.

Bluetooth BP Kiosk- A BLE based mobile application that helps consumers operate blood pressure kiosks and view their test results on Bluetooth enabled smartphones.

Al Ameen - Al Ameen is an Incident Reporting System which is a part of Dubai Police's e-governance initiative.

StocksPi- StocksPi is a subscription based long-term investment guide which is intended to help the users keep track of their investment in institutions such as banks and share market

iDent Connect- A messaging app that allows dentists, laboratories and implant sales representatives to collaborate and access treatment information.

aeCERT- A clone of the offocial aeCERT website that provides cyber security information to users.

Kibitz- A variant of tic-tac-toe using numbers 1, 2 and 3. Includes single player and multiplayer (online) modes.